[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle：那么，如果你还记得以前的话，回到我们的跟踪结帐，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: So, back to our track checkout if you recall from before,
关于电子商务的愚蠢场景。
that silly scenario about the eCommerce.
并且不是传递我的回调，如果我们将该API修改为
And rather than passing my callback in, what if we were to modify that API such
它向我们返回一个事件侦听器？
that it returns back an event listener to us?
正如你在第11行我听到的，
As you see on line 11 I listen to,
我收到了一个从track check out函数返回的侦听器，然后在第13行。
I receive a listener back from the track check out function and then on line 13.
我收听完成事件，当它结束时，我继续前进。
I listen to the completion event and when it finishes I move on.
我听错误事件，当它结束时，我继续前进。
And I listen to the error event and when it finishes I move on.
你能看到这是一个倒置的控制反转吗？
Can you see how that is an inverted the inversion of control or
而只是简单地保持控制？
rather just simply retain control?
因为现在不是将我的调用传递回那个实用程序，
Because now rather than passing my call back into that utility,
给他们王国的钥匙，让他们可以为所欲为
giving them the keys to the kingdom by which they can do whatever they want and
我不能相信他们不会做我意想不到的事。
I can't trust that they won't do what I don't expect.
我保留了控制权。
I've retained control.
我只是简单地说不，你只需要给我一个事件监听器，
I've simply said no you just give me an event listener,
我会想办法的。
I'll figure out what to do.
好的，我会听那个事件，我们可以把它连接起来，这样我们就可以听
Well I'll listen for that event and we could wire it such that we listen for
事件，然后在事件第一次发生时取消订阅该事件
the event and then unsubscribe to the event the first time it happens for
例如，就像我们完全控制了那个范例一样。
example, like we are in complete control of that paradigm.
所以，我们已经正常化，我们为这个过程带来了更多的理智，
So, we've normalized, we've brought more sanity back to this process,
而不是传递回调用。
rather than passing the call back in.
这是对承诺的重要理解，
That's an important understanding of promises,
就是他们颠倒了控制反转问题。
is that they uninvert the inversion of control problem.
这是件大事。
That's a big deal.
这不是一个小问题，这是最重要的问题之一。
That's not a small point, that's one of the most important points.
承诺的目的是为了扭转这种控制的反转。
Promises were designed to un-invert that inversion of control.
更确切地说，是为了保持这种控制权，以便所有这些信任问题
Rather, to retain that control, so that all of those trust issues
我们之前谈到的有一种有序和模式化的解决方法。
that we were talking about before have an ordered and patterned way of being solved.
现在，我们实际上并不是这样听的。
Now, we don't actually listen this way.
这不是大多数API的设计方式，不是。
This isn't how most APIs design, no.
虽然，这是一个我们至少可以理解的既定模式，但是
Although, it's an established pattern that we can at least understand, but
这是一种对承诺的思考的比喻。
it's It's a metaphor for thinking about a promise.
承诺就像一个事件侦听器。
A promise is like an event listener.
但是，不存在完成事件，我们将该事件称为Then事件。
But rather than there being a completion event, we call that event the then event.
这就是我们开始讨论承诺的API的地方。
And that's where we start to talk about the API of a promise.
所以，在卡车结账工具里。
So, in that truck checkout utility.
我们可以简单地创建承诺，而不是将回调作为参数接收
Rather than receiving a callback as a parameter we can simply create a promise
正如您在构建Promise实例的第二行中看到的那样。
as you see on line two on constructing a promise instance.
承诺的构造函数收到了两种方法：Resolve和Reject。
The constructor for the promise received two methods the resolve and the reject.
通过我给它们命名的方式，很清楚它们做了什么。
It's pretty clear what those do by the way I named them.
如果你想要解决承诺，如果你想完全履行承诺，你可以调用Resolve
You call resolve if you wanna resolve the promise if you want to fill it completely
或者是正确的，如果你需要拒绝承诺，你就叫拒绝。
or correctly and you call reject if you need to reject the promise.
回到我未来的芝士汉堡，这是唯一的两个选择。
Back to my future cheeseburger this is the only two options.
要么我最终会拿到我的芝士汉堡，要么这位女士会打电话给我
Either I'm eventually gonna get my cheeseburger or, the lady is going to call
我回到柜台，说这是个悲剧，但我们完全没有
me back up to the counter and say this is a tragedy but we are completely out of
芝士汉堡，我要把你的钱还给你。
cheeseburgers, I'm gonna have to give you your money back.
这是唯一的两个选择，对吧？
This is the only two options, right?
要么我拿到我的芝士汉堡要么拿回我的钱。
Either I get my cheeseburger or get my money back.
因此，我们既可以履行诺言召唤决心，也可以拒绝它。
So, we can either fulfill the promise calling resolve or we can reject it.
这是一个承诺所能产生的唯一两个结果。
Those are the only two outcomes that a promise can have.
所以，不管那个魔力是什么，我都会发布这些信息，因为那不是
So, whatever that magic is I'm alighting that information because that isn't
重要部分，但不管跟踪中逻辑是什么，检查和
the important part but whatever that logic is inside of track check out and
即使这是一个电话解决或拒绝。
even if it's a call resolve or reject.
现在，您注意到我们返回了Promise实例，所以
Now, you notice that we're returning that promise instance, so
当我们返回那个Promise实例时，我们将在代码中使用它。
when we return that promise instance we're going to use it in our code.
就像我在11号线上做的一样，我收到了一个承诺
Just like I'm doing here on line 11 I receive a promise back and
通知我们的第13行，而不是在完成时说点。
the notice our line 13 instead of saying dot on completion.
我说的是点，然后我要注册
I'm saying dot then I'm registering for
然后事件&gt；&gt；Kyle：Then事件将被调用
then event &gt;&gt; Kyle: The then event is gonna be called
当RESOLE或REJECT违背该承诺时。
when either resolve or reject is fired against that promise.
它将发射然后事件，如果你将比喻和
It will fire then event if you will metaphorically and
传递给它的两个函数中的一个将被调用。
one of those two functions passed into it's gonna get called.
如果成功履行承诺，将调用Finish
Finish will be called if the promise was fulfilled successfully
如果被拒绝，则出错。
error if it was rejected.
因此，我们实际上有一个很好的清洁机制
So, we have actually a nice clean mechanism for
被告知它是成功的或者是失败的。
being notified that it was either a success or that it was a failure.
这一点非常重要，向前迈进一步，进行控制反转。
It's incredibly important, step forward for an inversion of inversion of control.
控制反转有时是故意使用的。
Inversion of control is sometimes used in an intentional way.
框架设计作者有时会用到实际上，控制反转就是其中之一
Framework design author sometimes will use in fact, inversion of control is one
典型地被用来定义某事的关键特征
of the key characteristics that has classically been used to define something
作为一个框架，当您传入内容时，它会反转控制，它会调用
as a framework as when it inverts control when you pass in stuff in it calls for
是你而不是你在胡说八道。
you instead of you calling things.
我不知道你们中有多少人熟悉那些更经典的
I don't know how many of you are familiar with some of those more classical
关于软件设计的思考，但这是划分的特征之一
thinkings about software design but that's one of the characteristics that divides
库之间的框架是控制的反转。
between a library a framework is that inversion of control.
所以，有些人会告诉你，控制反转是故意的
So, some people will tell you that inversion of control is an intentional
设计功能和
design feature and
我会告诉你，就异步而言，这是一个糟糕的想法。
I would tell you as far as asynchronicity is concerned it's a terrible idea.
控制反转是通向黑暗面的途径，这里是
Inversion of control is the path to the dark side here it is
在我们的程序中，我们完全失去了所有的合理性的道路。
the path by which we completely lose all reasonability in our program.
所以，我们有意识地、积极地、有目的地尝试
So, we are trying intentionally actively on purpose
去颠覆这种模式，把它带回我们的控制之中。
to uninvert that paradigm to bring it back into our control.
这就是承诺为我们做的事情。
That's what promises are doing for us.
所以，这实际上根本不是关于API的。
So, this isn't actually about an API at all.
这不是缺少凹痕的问题。
This isn't about lack of indentation.
其实如果你密切关注，
In fact if you pay close attention,
你注意到这里仍然有大量的回调。
you notice there's still a ton of callbacks here.
事实上，这里的回调比以前更多。
In fact there's more callbacks here than they were before.
等一下，等等。
Wait a minute, hold up.
我以为承诺都是为了解决回调错误，摆脱回调
I thought promises were all about solving callback error, getting rid of callbacks
如果还牵涉到回调，他们到底要怎么修复任何东西？
how on earth are they fixing anything if there's still callbacks involved?
非常重要的问题。
Really important question.
如果仍然涉及回调，这个承诺系统如何
If there's still callbacks involved how does this promise system
给我们提供什么解决方案吗？
offer any solutions to us?
你可能会问，这是理所当然的。
You might ask and rightly so.
但是等等，如果我把我的回调传递到那个承诺中，
But wait, if I passed my callback into that promise,
承诺就不能多次给我回电吗？
can't the promise just call my callback a bunch of times?
我怎么能相信这个承诺去做它应该做的事情呢？
How can I trust the promise to do what it's supposed to do?
这是在这一点上可以提出的最重要的问题。
That's the most important question that can be asked at this point.
因为你需要明白承诺是设计好的
Because you need to understand that promises were designed
将信任灌输到此交易中。
to instill trust into this transaction.
它们只解决一次的基本设计原则，
The fundamental design principle that they're only resolved once,
它们只能作为成功解决，或者
they can only be resolved as a success, or
传递给承诺的消息总是保留的错误。
an error the messages that get passed to a promise are always kept.
它变得不可变，总是捕获异常，并且
It becomes immutable, exceptions are always caught and
变成了总是可以观察到的错误，没有任何东西被吞噬。
turned into errors that are always observable there's nothing swallowed.
如果你选择不观察是因为你懒惰或者
If you choose not to observe because you're lazy or
你犯了一个错误，那么它可能看起来像是被吞噬了，但它肯定是
you make a mistake, then it might look like it was swallowed but it definitely
并不是说你没有机会观察它们。
was not swallowed in the sense that you had no opportunity to observe them.
这是件大事。
This is a huge deal.
这是带回来的一大堆神志正常的人
This is a whole bunch of sanity brought back to
一个从根本上很难理解的过程
a process that has fundamentally been rather hard to understand and
很难维护整个JavaScript历史。
rather hard to maintain for the entirety of JavaScript history.
因此，在这里，我们确实开始看到API的一些好处。
So, here and we do start to see some of the benefits of the API.
这些都是超越时间独立状态这一概念的东西。
These are things above and beyond this notion of time independent state.
我说这很重要，这是我们的基础。
I said that was important, that's our foundation.
在此基础上，我们增加了所有的信任。
Built upon that, we have all of this trust added to it.
这主要是我们所得到的API中的机制，
And that is primarily the mechanism in the API that we've been given,
旨在以特定的方式组织我们的回调。
is designed to organize our callbacks in that certain way.
事实上，第三种思考承诺是什么的方式，
In fact, a third way of thinking about what a promise is,
它是一个回拨管理器。
is that it's a callback manager.
这是一种以可信的方式管理回调的模式。
It's a pattern for managing our callbacks in a trustable fashion.
&GT；&GT；Kyle：这是一件大事。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: That's a big deal.
这就是为什么承诺很重要，其实并不是那么重要
That's why promises matter, it's not really so
关于你是否喜欢闪亮的API。
much about whether you like the shiny API or not.
这并不是真的关于你是否想要摆脱嵌套或缩进。
It's not really about whether you wanna get rid of nesting or indentation.
有一个承诺地狱，很容易进入或没有银弹。
There is a promise hell and it's easy to get into or no silver bullet.
但有一件非常重要的事情是他们被设计来做的，那就是
But there's a really important thing that they've been designed to do that is to
重新向我们的系统灌输信任。
instill trust back into our systems.
甚至不仅仅是这样的信任。
Even more than just trust in this way.
现在我的值是不变的，我特意标记了这个值，因为现在请注意我的
Now that my value is immutable I mark that one on purpose because now mind that my
值从外部是不可变的，它不能更改。
value is immutable from the outside it cannot be changed.
这意味着我可以将该容器发送到我系统的任何端口，甚至可以发送到
That means I can send that container to any port of my system or even outside of
我的系统给其他第三方，我可以说，这是我的价值和
my system to other third parties and I can say, here is my value and
我不需要担心他们会改变我下面的价值。
I do not have to worry that they're gonna change that value out from underneath me.
还记得我们在另一个研讨会上讨论过不变性的问题吗？
Remember we talked about immutability in the other workshop and
这有多重要。
how important that is.
这是这些基本的进口之一。
That's one of these fundamental import.
事实上，最重要的事情之一是有外部不可变的。
In fact, one of the most important things is that there are externally immutable.
这里没有远距离的行动。
There's no action at a distance concern here.
如果你不知道“远距离行动”这个短语，那就是
If you don't know that phrase, action at a distance, that's one of the evils of
设计系统时的软件体系结构，远方的其他人可以
software architecture when you design a system, where somebody else far away can
在你不认识他的情况下做一些影响你的事情。
do something that affects you without you knowing him.
这不是个好主意。
It's a bad idea.
就像这里的一个小附注。
Just as a little side note here.
有关于未来版本的承诺的讨论
There are discussions happening around promises that in a future version of
JavaScript，我们可以让它成为可取消承诺的概念。
JavaScript, we can make it this notion of a cancellable promise.
我不会进入所有的政治
I'm not gonna go into all the politics and
所有围绕可取消承诺的疯狂。
all the craziness that's around cancelable promises.
简单地说，在我看来，这是一种摇摆狗的尾巴。
Just briefly to state to you, it's kind of a tail wagging the dog as far as I see it.
他们还有其他想要控制的东西
They have this other sort of thing that they want to control and
他们想要控制的东西只会暴露出承诺。
that thing that they want to control only exposes promises.
所以，让我们把承诺变成可取消的，这样我们就可以控制这件事。
And so, let's make promises cancelable so that we can control that thing.
而不是让那东西变得可控。
Instead of making that thing controllable.
这对我来说很疯狂，但你知道可取消的小承诺有什么不好吗？
It's crazy to me but you know what's bad about cancellable little promises?
远距离行动。
Action at a distance.
我有一个尚未解决的承诺。
I have a promise that's not yet resolved.
我把它传递给其他人，他们可以从我下面取消它。
I pass it to somebody else and they can cancel it out from underneath me.
怎么了？胡说八道。
What? That's nonsense.
这侵蚀了这些东西赖以建立的整个基础。
That erodes the entire foundation upon which these things are built.
所以，如果你看到我对可取消的承诺咆哮，这就是原因。
So, if you see me ranting about cancellable promises this is why.
我很认真地对待它，因为这是一件重要的事情。
I take it seriously because this is an important thing.
我们不应该仅仅因为我们沉迷于漂亮的API这个想法就把它扔掉。
We shouldn't throw it away just because we're drunk on this idea of pretty APIs.